## **Amah Martin**

## **Business Intelligence Engineer**

www.linkedin.com/in/amahmartin | www.github.com/ammartin8 | ammartin8842@gmail.com Louisville, KY

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

I'm a Business Intelligence Engineer with 5+ years of experience in data analysis, data visualization, and Python and SQL programming. I thrive in environments that allow me to take on the challenge of building solutions to solve inefficient processes and gather business intelligence that reveal challenges and guide business success for small, medium and large organizations.

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Languages: Python, SQL, M Query, DAX, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

Databases: PostgreSQL, SQLite, IBM Db2 on Cloud, Oracle, Redis

Tools & Systems: Anaconda, Jupyter Notebook, Microsoft Power BI, Toad Data Point, Toad Oracle, Microsoft Databricks, Azure DevOps, Miro, Power Query, CRM Storefront, Visual Studio Code, Tableau, Git, GitHub, Statistical Analysis Software (SAS), Figma

Interpersonal Skills: Data Analysis, Data Quality Assurance, Agile Methodology, Technical Writing, Automation, Project Management, Teamwork, Problem Solving, Troubleshooting, Customer Service

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Data and Reporting Professional | Data Analytical Rotational Experience (DARE) Associate

Humana – Louisville, KY

June 2021 - Present

- Completed 366+ hours of work items for the Marketing Analytics and Data team in a 4-month period in both an accurate and efficient manner that resulted in the success of completing business partner's goals and objectives
- Automated several Excel reports through the use of Power BI, SQL, and Python programming resulting increase productivity and saved 3+ hours of manual Excel work
- Managed to learn new processes and quickly adapt to an Agile work environment in a short period of time
- Maintain relationships with stakeholders in order to translate business requirements into technical requirements
- Provided streamlined reporting and analytics data to senior leadership for business intelligence (BI) visualizations to quickly identify growth areas and areas of opportunity.

### Advance Data Analytics Immersive Fellow

General Assembly - Remote

March 2021 - May 2021

• Completed 400+ hours of remote learning experience with a focus in analyzing real world dataset using tools such as Excel, PostgreSQL, Tableau, and Python

#### Contractor

Hallpoint Systems LLC, Louisville, KY

November 2020

- Developed a Power BI Dashboard for a Non-profit organization providing metrics on user progress in new Program
- Developed wireframes using Figma for visualization and feedback prior to building the final product
- Built a static multi-page website for a client using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap and JavaScript based on a Figma wireframe

#### **Epidemiologist | Quality Assurance Analyst**

June 2017 – March 2021

Cabinet for Health and Family Services, Frankfort, KY

- Automated several processes including an entire Vital Statistics Annual Report which increased productivity on tasks that has taken up to six hours to less than 30 minutes and was successful in meeting the deadline
- Responded to more than 150+ requests for vital statistics data in both an accurate and efficient manner that resulted in the success of completing client's organizational goals and objectives
- Translated business problems to IT staff, provide effective support in solving data quality assurance challenges that result in improving data quality and tasks efficiency for both clients and staff
- Received several awards by Supervisor, Branch Manager and Acting Director of Epidemiology and Health Planning for excellent work ethic and project accomplishments

#### **HIGHLIGHTED PROJECTS**

### Easy Budget App (https://github.com/ammartin8/easy-budget)

Developed an Expense Tracker application using Python 3 that will allow users to add, edit or delete records. In addition, users can view a breakdown summary and view charts showing the summary of expense and income data. Technologies used to create this app include Python 3, Peewee Object Relational Mapping, and SQLite.

### Git Technical Documentation Page (https://amahmartin.me/technical-doc-page/)

Developed and designed an interactive technical documentation page displaying a navigation bar, side-bar navigation, clean design demonstrating technical writing skills on getting started with the Git Version Control Tool. Users can interact with the website by clicking on each link in the sidebar and scroll to the appropriate section. Website follows WCAG guidelines and demonstrates responsive design.

#### **EDUCATION & PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT**

#### Microsoft, Remote

Certified in Azure Data Fundamentals

#### IBM, Remote

Python for Data Science SQL for Data Science Data Engineering Basics for Everyone Advance SQL for Data Engineers

# Python Data Structures, Remote Certificate of Completion

# Code Louisville Program, Louisville, KY Certificate of Completion

Front End Web Development (React JS, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap Framework) Back End Development (Python, SQL) Computational Thinking Independent Project

# Jefferson Community & Technical College, Louisville, KY Certificate in Programming

University of Kentucky, Lexington, KY Master of Public Health

Geographical Information Systems Statistical Analysis Software Advance Biostatistics